Guide to the Foreign Bondholders Protective Council Records
Department of Special Collections
- Series 1: Individual Country Negotiation File
  - Greece: correspondence with French council regarding Franc bonds of Greece (Box 126)
  - Greece: French league loans (Box 126)
  - Greece: league loan contract (Box 126)
  - Guatemala: league loan contract (Box 127)
  - Guatemala: negotiation file, 1934-1961 (Box 127)
  - Haiti: league loan contract (Box 127)
  - Haiti: negotiation file, 1922-1937 (Box 127)
  - Haiti: negotiation file, 1938-1954 (Box 128)
  - Hungary: negotiation file, 1936-1937 (Box 129)
  - Hungary: negotiation file, 1938-1956 (Box 130)
  - Hungary: negotiation file, 1957-1975 (Box 131)
  - Hungary: league loan contract (Box 131)
  - Hungary: settlement documents (Box 132)
  - Hungary: correspondence with Eliot Wadsworth (Box 132)
  - Hungary: extra copies of negotiation materials (Box 132)
  - Hungary: miscellaneous publications (Box 132)
  - Hungary: general inquiry letters, 1960s-1970s (Box 133)
  - Ireland: miscellaneous contracts, agreements, 1927 (Box 134)
  - Israel: negotiation file, 1951-1963 (Box 134)
  - Israel: miscellaneous contracts, agreements, various dates (Box 134)
  - Italy: negotiation file, 1934-1947 (Box 134)
  - Italy: negotiation file, 1947-1956 (Box 135)
  - Italy: Adjustment of Italian external obligations, proposed offer to adjust issues payable in Swiss Francs, June 10, 1949 (Box 136)
  - Italy: miscellaneous contracts, agreements, various dates (Box 136)
  - Japan: negotiation file, 1935-1947 (Box 137)
  - Japan: negotiation file, 1948-1952 (Box 138)
  - Japan: negotiation file, 1952-1955 (Box 139)
  - Japan: negotiation file, 1956-1975 (Box 140)
  - Japanese Sterling specimens (Box 140)
  - Memorandum to the Foreign Bondholders Protective Council regarding the Rights of Holders of Japanese Bonds sold outside the US, August 13, 1952 (Box 140)
  - Japan: miscellaneous contracts, agreements, various dates (Box 141)
  - Latvia: negotiation file, 1934-1956 (Box 142)
  - Latvia: miscellaneous contracts, agreements, various dates (Box 142)
  - Liberia: miscellaneous contracts, agreements, various dates (Box 142)
  - Lithuania: negotiation file, 1934-1956 (Box 142)
  - Mexico: correspondence (Box 142)
  - Mexico: miscellaneous contracts, agreements, various dates (Box 142)
  - Mexico: negotiation file, 1930-1966 (Box 143)
  - Netherlands: negotiation file, 1934-1958 (Box 144)
  - Netherlands: miscellaneous contracts, agreements, various dates (Box 144)
  - Norway: negotiation file, 1936-1961 (Box 144)
  - Norway: miscellaneous contracts, agreements, various dates (Box 144)
  - Panama: negotiation file, 1934-1939 (Box 145)
  - Panama: negotiation file, 1939-1955 (Box 146)
  - Panama: miscellaneous contracts, agreements, various dates (Box 147)
  - Peru: negotiation file, 1933-1937 (Box 147)
  - Peru: negotiation file, 1938-1943 (Box 148)
  - Peru: negotiation file, 1944-1945 (Box 149)
  - Peru: negotiation file, 1946-1949 (Box 150)
  - Peru: negation file, 1953-1963 (Box 151)
  - Confidential file regarding Peruvian lawsuit, 1953-1955 (Box 151)
  - Republic of Peru General Bond, 3% sinking fund dollar bonds due January 1, 1997 (Box 151)
  - Peru: miscellaneous contracts, agreements, various dates (Box 151)
  - Philippines: negotiation file, 1937-1956 (Box 152)
  - Poland: negotiation file, 1934-1937 (Box 152)
  - Poland: negotiation file, 1937-1951 (Box 153)
  - Poland: negotiation file, 1952-1975 (Box 154)
  - Poland: General inquiry letters, 1960s and 1970s (Box 155)
  - Poland: General inquiry letters, 1960s and 1970s (Box 156)
  - Poland: General inquiry letters, 1960s and 1970s (Box 157)
  - Poland: General inquiry letters, 1960s and 1970s (Box 158)
  - Poland: General inquiry letters, 1960s and 1970s (Box 159)
  - Poland: General inquiry letters, 1960s and 1970s (Box 160)
  - Poland: General inquiry letters, 1960s and 1970s (Box 161)
  - Poland: General inquiry letters, 1960s and 1970s (Box 162)
  - Poland: General inquiry letters, 1960s and 1970s (Box 163)
  - Poland: General inquiry letters, 1960s and 1970s (Box 164)
  - Poland: General inquiry letters, 1980s (Box 164)
  - Poland: negotiation file, Danzig, 1937-1976 (Box 165)
  - Poland: extra negotiation file materials, various dates (Box 165)
  - Poland contributions file, 1942-1951 (Box 165)
  - Poland and Hungary: financial statistics (Box 165)
  - Poland: statistical information (Box 165)
  - Poland: Correspondence regarding Spurr, E. W. (Box 165)
  - Poland: Correspondence regarding Drake, Colonel J. F. (Box 165)
  - Poland: General inquiry letters, 1970s and 1980s (Box 166)
  - Poland and Danzig: original signed copy of the "Agreed Minute," February 1975 (Box 166)
  - Poland: miscellaneous contracts, agreements, various dates (Box 166)
  - Poland: miscellaneous contracts, agreements, various dates (Box 167)
  - Romania: negotiation file, 1934-1938 (Box 167)
  - Romania: negotiation file, 1939-1974 (Box 168)
  - Romania: Miscellaneous letters and draft agreements (Box 169)
  - Romania: contracts (Box 169)
  - Romania: miscellaneous correspondence regarding Romania Debt (Box 169)
  - Russia: negotiation file, 1902-1942 (Box 169)
  - Russia: negotiation file, 1943-1974 (Box 170)
  - Russia: miscellaneous contracts, agreements, various dates (Box 170)
  - Russia: miscellaneous correspondence regarding Russian Debt (Box 170)
  - Saarland: negotiation file, 1947-1966 (Box 171)
  - Uruguay: negotiation file, 1934-1937 (Box 172)
  - Uruguay: negotiation file, 1938-1954 (Box 173)
  - Uruguay: miscellaneous contracts, agreements, various dates (Box 174)
  - Venezuela: negotiation file, 1938-1946 (Box 174)
  - Yugoslavia: negotiation file, 1933-1937 (Box 174)
  - Yugoslavia: negotiation file, 1938-1949 (Box 175)
  - Yugoslavia: negotiation file, 1949-1957 (Box 176)
  - Yugoslavia: miscellaneous contracts, agreements, various dates (Box 176)
  - Yugoslavia: negotiation file, 1958-1972 (Box 177)
  - Yugoslavia contributions file, 1960-1974 (Box 177)
  - Yugoslavia Plan and agreement, general fund, indenture and general bond, 1936 (Box 177)
  - Miscellaneous countries: extra copies of negotiation materials, agreements, drafts (not sorted) (Box 178)
  - Miscellaneous countries: extra copies of negotiation materials, agreements, drafts (not sorted) (Box 179)
- Series 2: Administrative records
  - Subseries 2.1: Board files
    - Certificate of Incorporation, originals and copies, 1933-1934 (Box 180, Folder 1)
    - Organization Papers/Memorandums to the Board, 1933-1935 {this folder contains an FDR memo (unsigned) and a White House press release) (Box 180, Folder 2)
    - Bylaws of Foreign Bondholders Protective Council, 1954 and 1975 (Box 180, Folder 3)
    - Certificate of Copyright Registration for FBPC's annual reports, 1937-1949 (Box 180, Folder 4)
    - Special Board of Directors correspondence, 1971-1982 (Box 180, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous materials pertaining to annual FBPC board of directors meetings, 1979-1983 (Box 180, Folder 6)
    - Annual meeting agenda packets, 1959-1983 (Box 180, Folder 7)
    - Annual meeting agenda packets, 1984-1987 (Box 180, Folder 8)
    - Annual meeting notice and proxies, 1986 (Box 180, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous report published by the Board, 1968-1975 (Box 180, Folder 10)
    - Press Releases of the FBPC, 1940-1973 (Box 181)
    - Annual reports 1934, 1936-1945 (Box 182)
    - Annual reports 1946-1967 (Box 183)
    - Presentation copies of annual reports 1959-65, 1967, 1971-1982, 1985 (Box 184)
    - Working papers of various banks' outstanding debts for council's report 1968-1970 (Box 185)
    - (4) Secretaries steno notepads containing memos, letters, telephone calls 1968-1971. All in short-hand. (Box 186)
    - Copies of letterhead (Box 186)
    - Appointment books 1984-1988 (Box 186)
    - Province of Buenos Aires: readjustment plan of 1935 (Othertype 187)
    - Republic of Peru: debt readjustment, 1953 (Othertype 187)
    - Debt Readjustment: Province of Mendoza (Argentina): 1938 Offers to holders of external 7.50% secured sinking fund gold bonds, dated December 1, 1926, due June 1, 1951 (Othertype 188)
    - Republic of Uruguay: readjustment offer of 1937 (Othertype 188)
    - Republic of Uruguay: offer to holders of outstanding dollar bonds of City of Montevideo, 1938 (Othertype 188)
    - Minutes 1933-1935 (Box 197)
    - Minutes 1936-1937 (Box 198)
    - Minutes 1938-1940 (Box 199)
    - Minutes 1941-1945 (Box 200)
    - Minutes 1946-1949 (Box 201)
    - Minutes 1950-1953 (Box 202)
    - Minutes 1954-1956 (Box 203)
    - Minutes 1957-1959 (Box 204)
    - Minutes 1960-1963 (Box 205)
    - Minutes 1964-1967 (Box 206)
    - Minutes 1968-1973 (Box 207)
    - Minutes 1974-1977 (Box 208)
    - Minutes 1978-1983 (Box 209)
    - Minutes 1984-1985 (Box 209)
  - Subseries 2.2: Richard Dine Files
    - Correspondence regarding Bolivia, 1986-1988 (Box 189)
    - Correspondence regarding Bulgaria, 1987 (Box 189)
    - Correspondence regarding China, 1979-1988 (Box 189)
    - Correspondence regarding Czechoslovakia, 1985-1986 (Box 189)
    - Correspondence regarding Czechoslovakia, 1987-1988 (Box 190)
    - Correspondence regarding Germany, 1984-1988 (Box 190)
    - Correspondence regarding Hungary, 1987-1988 (Box 190)
    - Correspondence regarding Italy, 1988 (Box 190)
    - Correspondence regarding Peru, 1987 (Box 190)
    - Correspondence regarding Poland, 1974-1988 (Box 190)
    - Correspondence regarding Russia, 1986-1988 (Box 191)
    - Correspondence regarding Russia: memo regarding British/Soviet Settlement, 1986 (Box 191)
    - Correspondence regarding Russia: Financial Committee of the US-USSR trade and economic council (ASTEC) annual meeting, 1986 (Box 191)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence and meeting notes, 1980s (Box 191)
    - Correspondence with the Department of State, 1980 (Box 191)
    - Administrative: miscellaneous correspondence, drafts of minutes, meeting agendas, 1986-1988 (Box 192)
    - Administrative: miscellaneous financial materials, 1986-1988 (Box 192)
    - Administrative: papers pertaining to Muldowney, CPA, 1985-1986 [auditor for the council for years 1985-1986] (Box 192)
    - Administrative: press clippings regarding Marine Midland Chairman CEO and Foreign Bondholders President, John R. Petty, 1986 (Box 192)
    - Administrative: legislative research on trade issues, 1984-1986 (Box 193)
    - Administrative: legislative research on House of Representative Congressional Hearings, 1972 (Box 193)
    - Administrative: photocopies of published works (Box 193)
    - Administrative: Marine Midland correspondence regarding debt securities issued by lesser-developed countries (LDC Debt Issue) (Box 194)
    - Administrative: materials pertaining to the Leveraged Buyouts 1988 Seminar run by The Management Exchange in New York. (Box 195)
    - Analysis on the electronic components distribution Industry (Box 195)
    - Administrative: Marine Midland Credit Policy Guide (Box 196)
  - Subseries 2.3: Working files
    - Kenneth M. Spang's personal correspondence file (Box 210, Folder 1)
    - Letters from Kenneth M. Spang to James Grafton Rogers, Esq., 1952 (Box 210, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous board letters and memos, 1936-1980 (Box 210, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous board letters and memos, 1945-1953 (Box 210, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous board letters and memos, 1954-1959 (Box 210, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous board letters and memos, 1960-1976 (Box 210, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence regarding fifty year study of American investment in foreign dollar bonds, 1950s (Box 210, Folder 7)
    - Department of State correspondence, 1937-1942 (Box 210, Folder 8)
    - Department of State correspondence, 1942-1955 (Box 210, Folder 9)
    - Department of State correspondence, 1954-1972 (Box 210, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence with Council of Foreign Bondholders in London, 1950-1960 (Box 211, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence with Council of Foreign Bondholders in London, 1960-1972 (Box 211, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence with Association Nationale in Paris, 1963-1965 (Box 211, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence with Committee of Amsterdam Stock Exchange, 1950-1970 (Box 211, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence with Foreign Claims Settlement Commission, 1950s-1960s (Box 211, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence with Foreign Claims Settlement Commission, 1950-1960s (Box 211, Folder 6)
    - Foreign Claims Settlement Commission reports to Congress, 1950s-1960s (Box 211, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence with U.S. Government Printing Office, 1960s-1970s (Box 212, Folder 1)
    - Fiscal Agents Letters 1976 (Box 212, Folder 2)
    - Fiscal Agents Letters 1977 (Box 212, Folder 3)
    - Foreign securities tax/Interest equalization tax (balance of payments), 1960s-1970s (Box 212, Folder 4)
    - International Monetary Fund, 1958-1978 (Box 212, Folder 5)
    - International Centre for Settlement of Investment Disputes, 1960s-1970s (Box 212, Folder 6)
    - International Bank for Reconstruction and Development (World Bank), 1959-1980 (Box 212, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence relating to Banca Commerciale Italiana (Box 213, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence relating to Bankers Trust Company (Box 213, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence relating to Barclays Bank (Box 213, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence relating to BIA-BIK-BO (Box 213, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence relating to Briggs, Henry P. & Company (Box 213, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence relating to Buscheck, Alfred J. (Box 213, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence relating to Carl Marks & Company, Inc. (Box 213, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence relating to DeVed, G. Richard (Box 213, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence relating to International Match Corp. (Box 213, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence relating to Mercantile Trust Company (Box 213, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence relating to Neta Murphy (Box 213, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence relating to New York Match Company, Inc. (Box 213, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence relating to Price, Waterhouse & Company (Box 213, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence relating to Serrecchia, Joseph (Box 213, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence relating to Steinbrecher, Teresa (Box 213, Folder 15)
    - General filing letters, 1950s-1980s (Box 214)
    - General filing letters, 1960s-1980s (Box 215)
    - Current letters, 1960s (Box 215)
    - Unfiled letters, 1940s-1960s (Box 215)
    - Unfiled letters by alpha (Box 215)
    - Miscellaneous letters requesting Prospectus (Box 215)
    - General correspondence regarding Bolivia and Poland (Box 216)
    - General correspondence regarding Russian bonds (Box 216)
    - General correspondence, 1937-1961 (Box 216)
    - General correspondence (Answered but unsorted), 1968-1987 (Box 217)
    - General correspondence postmarked 1985, opened after January 30, 1986 (Box 217)
    - Returned correspondence, 1986 (Box 217)
    - Papers pertaining to A.L.M. Kadragic and Nelson Bengston (Box 218, Folder 1)
    - Description sheets used for records management, 1976 (Box 218, Folder 2)
    - Inter-American Development Bank, Washington, DC, 1960-1961 (Box 218, Folder 3)
    - Caisse Commune & Ottoman debts (Box 218, Folder 4)
    - Excerpts from official report of proceeding before the securities and exchange commission, Haiti, Brazil, Chile, 1935 (Box 218, Folder 5)
    - League loans correspondence (Othertype 219)
    - League loans committees (Othertype 219)
    - League loans committee correspondence with Thomas W. Lamont (Othertype 219)
    - League loans committee correspondence with James Speyer (Othertype 219)
    - League loans committee drafts for May 20, 1950 report (Othertype 219)
    - Press release announcing establishment of Board of Visitors for the Foreign Bondholders Protective Council, 1937 (Box 220)
    - Correspondence and other materials pertaining to the Board of Visitors relations with the US government, 1937-1975 (Box 220)
    - Diplomatic list, February and August, 1980 (Box 220)
    - Foreign Bondholders Protective Council financial statements 1964-1970, 1974-1979, 1980-1986 (Box 221)
    - Foreign Bondholders Protective Council Incorporated financial statement file, 1934-1971 (Box 221)
    - Financial statements for Foreign Bondholders board meetings, 1957-1959 (Box 221)
    - Check registers, 1979-1985 (Box 221)
    - Financial research (early financing) (Box 221)
    - Early advances confidential file (Box 221)
    - Ledger: sheets from second ledger (inactive accounts), 1946-1969 (Box 222)
    - Ledger: cash book records, 1950-1955 (Box 222)
    - Ledger: cash book, 1934-1949 (Box 223)
    - Ledger: trial balance, 1934-1956 (Box 223)
    - Payroll 1936-1953, 1959-1964, 1965-1970 (Box 224)
    - Wage stabilization regulations, 1952 (Box 224)
    - Withholding Federal and New York state income taxes, 1959-1979 (Box 225)
    - New York City business tax, 1935-1967 (Othertype 226)
    - General Business and financial tax, New York City, 1952-1957 (Othertype 226)
    - Commercial rent or occupancy tax, 1939-1967 (Othertype 226)
    - New York City sales tax, 1938-1965 (Othertype 226)
    - Report sales and gifts, 1960-1962 (Othertype 226)
    - General Business and financial tax forms not filled out (Othertype 226)
    - Federal tax information: TFR-500 Census of Property in Foreign Countries form, 1943 (Box 227)
    - Various federal tax reform acts, various years (Box 227)
    - United States Treasury Department Form 990: Tax exempt organizations, 1955-1970 (Box 227)
    - Maryland tax information: returns and correspondence, 1939-1962 (Box 227)
    - Maryland state report and tax service, 1948 (Box 227)
    - Maryland income and property tax returns for United States Corporation Company, 1952-1984 (Box 227)
    - Miscellaneous notes, tax returns and correspondence (Box 228)
    - Tax returns, 1950-1958 (Box 228)
    - New York disability insurance, 1950-1962 (Box 229)
    - New York state disability fund regulations, schedules, 1949-1978 (Box 229)
    - Liability Insurance Policy, 1957-1970 (Box 229)
    - Commercial blanket bond insurance, 1947-1979 (Box 229)
    - Correspondence regarding various building leases, 1945-1988 (Box 229)
    - New York unemployment insurance, 1952-1967 (Box 230)
    - Bills paid: vouchers, 1934-1951 (missing 1943) (Box 231)
    - Bills paid, 1959-1985 (Box 232)
    - Financial file containing miscellaneous correspondence, 1975-1977 (Box 232)
    - Bills paid: consultants by alpha (Box 233)
    - Johnson Act, 1934-1945 (Othertype 234)
    - Various information on Latin America (Othertype 234)
    - Lea Bill, 1937 (Othertype 234)
    - Securities Act of 1933 (Othertype 234)
    - First National City Bank of New York statement on taxation of foreign income (Othertype 234)
    - Confidential correspondence file relating to legislation (Othertype 234)
    - Information on foreign assets in the United States (form TFR 300) (Othertype 234)
    - Foreign Claims Settlement Commission of the United States reports, various years (Othertype 235)
  - Subseries 2.4: Publications
    - Miscellaneous United States congressional and federal commission hearing and reports, various years (Box 236)
    - Miscellaneous United States congressional and federal commission hearing and reports, various years (Box 237)
    - Miscellaneous reports of foreign origin, various countries (Box 238)
    - Miscellaneous United States Government documents, various years (Box 239)
    - Miscellaneous United States Government documents, various years (Box 240)
    - Miscellaneous publications, academic reports and unpublished thesis (Box 241)
    - Association Suisse des Banquiers, Rapport 1961-1971 (Box 242)
    - Association Suisse des Banquiers Bale, Rapport du Jubile, 1912-1962 (Box 242)
    - Rapport, Association Nationale des Porteurs Francais de Valeurs Mobilieres, 1958-1964, 1968-1969, 1972 (Box 242)
    - Quarterly Economic Review, 1972-1973 (Box 242)